Guide to the Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1834-1980 CAM.NEV.1987.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Clippings, 1888-1947; IV.
  - Concerts, 1886-1902; 1.
    - Program Announcement, December 6, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 223)
      University of Pittsburgh News.. Not in Wang list or Word document.
    - Untitled, January 8, 1902 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 224)
      The Pittsburg[h] Dispatch
  - Social events, 1888-1893; 2.
    Arrangement by chronological order.
    - Wedding, January 5, 1888 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 225)
      Pittsburgh Commercial Gazette. Photocopies of articles also available in separate folders.
    - Art Society reception, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 226)
      Three clippings of pre-event announcement, stored in individual folders. "Untitled," pre-event announcement, Jan. 12, 1893. "Art Society Reception"; pre-event announcement. "A composer Honored" Pittsburgh Commercial Gazette, Fri., Jan. 13, 1893. 2 copies. "The Nevin Reception," The Pittsburgh Times, Fri. Jan. 13, 1893. 2 copies. "Received by the Art Society," The Pittsburgh Dispatch, Jan. 13, 1893. "Untitled," The Post, Jan. 13, 1893.
    - Reception of Mr. and Mrs. E. W. N. by Mr. & Mrs. Robert P. Nevin, Edgewater, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 227)
      Thursday evening.
    - Untitled, January 13, 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 228)
      The Pittsburgh Post. Not in Wang list or Word document.
  - Obituaries and Related Events, 1901-1947; 3.
    - Article Scrapbook (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 229)
      This section contains articles pertaining to Nevin's death as reported by newspapers throughout the US. They are organized by pasted articles first, then the articles stored loosely in two manilla envelopes within the scrapbook. Not mentioned in the Wang list or the Word document version of the finding aid. Page numbers for each obit are listed in the scope and contents of the specific items.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, Composer is Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item a)
        New York Herald, article scrapbook page 3. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Nevin, the Composer, Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item b)
        New York Times, article scrapbook page 3. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Death of Composer Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item c)
        NY Sun, article scrapbook page 3. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item d)
        New York World, article scrapbook page 4. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, Composer of "Narcissus," Is Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item e)
        New York Journal, scrapbook page 4. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item f)
        New York Evening Post. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item g)
        New York Commercial Advertiser. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item h)
        New York Mail & Express. Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin.
      - [Untitled], 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item i)
        Obituary of Ethelbert Nevin. New York Evening Telegram
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item j)
        North American, Philadelphia, PA.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dies Suddenly, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item k)
        The Philadelphia Press. Scrapbook page 6.
      - He Wrote "Narcissus" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item l)
        The Philadelphia Times. Scrapbook pages 6-7.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item m)
        The Boston Herald. Scrapbook page 7.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item n)
        The Boston Journal. Scrapbook pages 7-8.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item o)
        The Boston Globe. Article scrapbook page 8.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item p)
        The Chronicle, Chicago IL. Scrapbook page 8.
      - Death of Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item q)
        Chicago Times Herald. Scrapbook page 8.
      - Ethelbert Nevin is Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item r)
        Chicago Tribune. Scrapbook page 9.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dies, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item s)
        Chicago North American. Scrapbook page 9.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Has Passed Away, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item t)
        Buffalo Enquirer, scrapbook page 9.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item u)
        Buffalo Express, scrapbook page 9.
      - Nevin, the Composer, Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item v)
        Albany Journal, scrapbook page 10.
      - Death of an American Composer, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item w)
        Albany Argus. Scrapbook page 10.
      - Famous Musician Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item x)
        Democrat Chronicle, Rochester, NY.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item y)
        Observer, Utica, NY.
      - Composer Ethelbert W. Nevin Dies Suddenly in New Haven., 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item z)
        Pittsburg[h] Times. Scrapbook pages 11 - 16.
      - EW. Nevin, The Composer, Dead., 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item aa)
        The Pittsburg[h] Leader. Scrapbook pages 17-25.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item bb)
        Chronicle Telegraph, Pittsburgh, PA. Scrapbook page 25.
      - Composer Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item cc)
        Pittsburg[h] Post. Scrapbook page 26-27.
      - Nevin Died Suddenly in New Haven of Heart Disease, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item dd)
        Citizen, Colombus OH. Scrapbook page 27.
      - Ethelbert Nevin is Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ee)
        Kansas City Star. Scrapbook pages 28-29
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ff)
        Lancaster Examiner, scrapbook page 28.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item gg)
        Hartford Telegram, scrapbook page 29.
      - Composer of "Narcissus is Dead", 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item hh)
        Cleveland Leader, Scrapbook page 30.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ii)
        Pioneer Press, St. Paul, MN. Scrapbook page 30.
      - Nevin is Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item jj)
        American, Waterbury, CT. Scrapbook page 31.
      - [Untitled], 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item kk)
        Herald, Agusta, GA. Obituary statement.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ll)
        Cleveland Plain Dealer. Scrapbook page 31.
      - An American Composer, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item mm)
        Wisconsin, Milwaukee WS. Scrapbook pg 31-32.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item nn)
        Indianapolis Journal, scrapbook page 32.
      - Musical Composer Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item oo)
        Baltimore American, scrapbook page 32
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item pp)
        Evening Telegram, Portland OR, scrapbook page 33.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item qq)
        Dayton Herald. Scrapbook page 33.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dies, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item rr)
        Telegram, Worcester, Mass. Scrapbook page 33
      - Death of Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ss)
        News Tribune, Duluth, Minn. Scrapbook page 33.
      - Composer Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item tt)
        Oregonian, Portland, OR. Scrapbook page 34
      - Nevin Passes Away, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item uu)
        Indianapolis Sentinel. Scrapbook page 34.
      - Composer Nevin Dies (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item vv)
        World Herald, Omaha, NE. Scrapbook Page 38.
      - Death of Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ww)
        Spokesman Review, Spokane, Washington. Scrapbook page 39
      - Famous Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item xx)
        The Messenger, St. Albans, VT. Scrapbook page 35.
      - Ethelbert Nevin Dead, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item yy)
        The Minneapolis Times, scrapbook page 35.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item zz)
        The Ledger, Tacoma, WA, scrapbook page 35.
      - Noted American Composer, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item aaa)
        The Republican, Denver, CO. Page 36.
      - Nevin, Composer, 02/18/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item bbb)
        Bee, Omaha NE, scrapbook pg. 36.
      - Ethelbert Nevin's Career is Prematurely Closed, 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ccc)
        Times, Philadelphia, PA, scrapbook page 36.
      - Nevin's Funeral, 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ddd)
        Philadelphia Press, scrapbook page 37.
      - [Untitled], 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item eee)
        Observer, Utica, NY, scrapbook Page 37.
      - Composer Nevin Dead, 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item fff)
        Herald, Rochester, NY, scrapbook page 37.
      - Nevin's Body Will Be Taken to Sewickley, 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ggg)
        Dispatch, Pittsburg[h], PA, scrapbook pages 37-38.
      - Ethelbert Nevin's Funeral (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item hhh)
        Times, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook Page 39
      - [Untitled], 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item iii)
        Milwaukee Sentinel, scrapbook page 39
      - Services From the Church: Funeral of Ethelbert Nevin Will Take Place Wednesday, 02/19/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item jjj)
        Post, Pittsburg[h], PA, scrapbook page 39.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item kkk)
        Musical Courier, New York City. Scrapbook page 39.
      - Ethelbert Nevin: The Famous Composer, Well Known in This City, is Dead (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item lll)
        Gazette, Elmira, NY. Scrapbook page 40
      - A Tribute to Nevin, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item mmm)
        Post Express, Rochester, NY, scrapbook pages 39 - 40.
      - [Untitled], 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item nnn)
        Post Express, Rochester, NY. Page 40.
      - [Untitled], 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ooo)
        Utica Press. Obituary on EWN. Pages 40-41.
      - Nevin's Music in Favor, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ppp)
        Dispatch, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook page 41.
      - Narcissus and Roses, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item qqq)
        Palladium, New Haven, CT. Scrapbook page 41.
      - Ethelbert Nevin (Communicated), 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item rrr)
        Journal Courier, New Haven, CT. Scrapbook Page 42
      - Will Arrive This Morning, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item sss)
        Commercial Gazette, Harrisburg, PA. Scrapbook Page 42
      - Ethelbert Nevin's Funeral, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item ttt)
        Post, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook Page 42
      - Funeral of Ethelbert Nevin, 02/20/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item uuu)
        Chronicle Telegraph, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook page 43.
      - Nevin's Melodies Were Blended in a Soft Requiem, 02/21/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item vvv)
        Dispatch, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook pages 43 - 46 (printed images pages 45-46).
      - Narcissus Covered Dead Composer's Casket, 02/21/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item www)
        Post, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook page 44.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, the Composer is Buried, 02/21/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item xxx)
        Spy, Worcester, Mass. Scrapbook page 44.
      - [Untitled], 02/22/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item yyy)
        Dispatch, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook page 44.
      - Memorial to Nevin, 02/23/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item zzz)
        Press, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook page 44.
      - [Untitled], 02/23/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item aaaa)
        The New York Times. Scrapbook Page 45.
      - Fine Tribute to Ethelbert Nevin, 02/23/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item bbbb)
        Post, Pittsburg[h], PA. Scrapbook page 45.
      - Ethelbert Nevin, 02/24/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item cccc)
        Herald, Rochester NY. Scrapbook pages 46-47.
      - [Untitled], 03/08/1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item dddd)
        Musical Courier, London, England. Scrapbook page 47.
      - Portrait of Nevin over "Narcissus", 1891 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item eeee)
        Unidentified Newspaper. Scrapbook page 49.
    - "Death of Ethelbert Nevin", 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 230)
      The[New York] Dramatic Mirror. February.
    - "A Beautiful Tribute: Eastern Writer's Fitting Words on the Death of Ethelbert Nevin (Dramatic Mirror).", 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 231)
      February.
    - "Ethelbert Nevin Dies at New Haven: Pittsburgh's Famous Musician Passes Away After a Brief Illness.", 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 232)
      [The Pittsburgh Leader], [Feb. 18], p. 8.
    - "His Music Lives", February 20, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 233)
      Unidentified newspaper.
    - "Nevin Funeral Has Been Arranged", February 19, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 234)
      Presented to the University by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - "Funeral of Mr. Nevin", February 20, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 235)
    - "Ethelbert Nevin (Communicated)" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 236)
    - "Funeral of Robert P. Nevin", June 28, 1908 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 237)
      Robert P. Nevin is the father of E.W.N. Presented to the University by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - Florence Barclay, Novelist, is Dead, March 11, 1921 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 238)
      Florence Barclay wrote "The Rosary," the novel. Presented to the University by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - "Henry Buxton says... Widow of Ethelbert Nevin Has Built 'Riviera Estate' On Shore of Bluehill Bay: Home Designed by Maine Architect Reproduces Scenes Loved by Composer of 'The Rosary'; Mrs. Nevin Tells How Song Was Written.", September 2, 1937 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 239)
      The Bangor Daily News, Bangor, Maine. Thurs. Presented to the University by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - Disinters Nevin Body Over Kin's Protest, May 21, 1938 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 240)
      Pittsburgh Sun Telegraph. Photocopy. Not in Wang list or Word document.
    - "Widow Moves Body: Nevin's Admirers Protest", May 22, [1938] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 241)
    - MISSING "Ethelbert Nevin's Body Taken From Grave Here." "Widow Orders Removal of Composer's Remains to New Shrine in Maine 37 years after Death.", 1938; m. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 242)
      Pittsburgh Sun Telegraph. In "Oversize Items." Presented to the University by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - MISSING Prized Nevin Possessions Are Given to the University, May 23, 1937; n. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 243)
      Pittsburgh Press, In "Oversized Items."
    - MISSING [Untitled], April 30, 1947; o. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 244)
      Pittsburgh Sun-Telegraph
    - MISSING Original "Mighty Lak'a Rose" Manuscript Presented by Widow of Its Composer, p. (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 245)
      Pitt News
  - Others, 4.
    Arrangement of articles by subjects.
    - Biographical, A.
      - "Untitled", 1887 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 246)
        The Dispatch, Before E. W. N. left Pittsburgh for Boston. Clipping kept by Tom Dickson. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - Pennsylvania and Pittsburgh Musicians, B.
      - "Brilliant Gems of Music Composed by Gifted Pittsburgers", March 26, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 247)
        The Pittsburgh Leader., Sunday. Includes: Ad. Foester, Fidelis Zitterbart, Ehtelbert Nevin, Arthur Nevin, Carl Retter, Charles Davis Carter, Leo Oehmler, Prof. Guenther.
      - "Interesting Sketch of Penna. Musicians", February 3, 1923 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 248)
        The Sewickley Herald. Includes: Stephen Foster, Ethelbert Nevin, Charles Cadman, and Henry Burleigh.
      - "Accomplishments of a Pittsburger", 1893 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 249)
        Pittsburgh. Article focuses on Nevin's compositions and how they refect Pittsburgh's influence on American songs.
      - "Untitled", January 24, 1962 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 250)
        The Sewickley Herald
    - About "Mighty Lak'a Rose" the play, C.
      - "A Crook Story that is Entirely Different and a Sure fire Entertainment: Edwin Carewe presents 'Mighty Lak'a Rose.", 1923 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 251)
        The Film Daily, p. 139. Missing.
      - "Edwin Carewe Presents 'Mighty Lak'a Rose': A Symphony of Life in the High and Low Places", February 17, 1923 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 252)
        The Saturday Evening Post, p. 139.
      - Nevin's Work Theme for Picture Production, February 1923 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 252.1)
    - About the Rosary, D.
      - "Untitled", February 14, 1925 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 253)
        The Saturday Evening Post.
      - "Author of 'The Rosary,' The Late Father Thomas Whalen Said to Have Written Song's Words", 1924 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 254)
      - "Untitled" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 255)
        Bohemian Magazine, concerns "The Rosary"
      - MISSING"Untitled", 1924 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 256)
        Words and Music column, in unidentified newspaper. Presented to the University by Elizabeth Dickson.
    - Miscellaneous, E.
      - "Untitled", May 16, 1894 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 256)
        The Pittsburgh Dispatch. Contains a letter from E.W.N. to the music editor, expressing gratitude to Hans von Buelow, at Buelow's death. Boston.
      - "The Hosiery" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 257)
        A poem. Presented to the University of Pittsburgh by Elizabeth Dickson.
- Articles, 1889-1922; V.
  This series consists of articles written about Ethelbert Nevin, the majority of which were written in tribute after his death. Some of the articles deal with the University of Pittsburgh planned Ethelbert Nevin room.
  - Cather, Willa Sibert. "The Passing Show: An Evening at Vineacre.", 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 258)
    The Courier. Framed. In oversized items.
  - Cather, Willa Sibert. "The Passing Show: An Evening at Vineacre", 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 259)
    The Courier. Photostatic Copy. Accompanied by: a letter from John March, assistant librarian of Univ. of Oklahoma, to R.C.M. (Oct. 6, 1949); a reply letter to March from Edwina Green, sec. to R.C.M., Oct. 19, 1949.
  - Cather, Willa Sibert. "The Man who Wrote 'Narcissus'", 1900 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 2, Folder 260)
    Ladies' Home Journal, Two copies. Framed copy located in oversized item drawer, cabinet 18, drawer 2
  - Ethelbert Nevin Program, KDKA to NBC, November 25, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 261)
    6:15 - 6:45 p.m. The last broadcast from Sewickley.
  - "Eva Mylott's Favorite Song Carried to the Far Corners of the Earth." (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 262)
  - "Florence L. Barclay, Author of 'The Rosary': A Story of A Her Personality and Work", December 11, 1913 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 264)
    The British Weekly, P. 33
  - Gough, Mary Stowell. A Sketch of Ethelbert Nevin, December 15, 1905 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 265)
    [5] sheets. Typescript copy, with corrections in ink and pencil. Plattsburgh, N.Y.
  - [Mrs. Gounley's Sketch of E. N.] (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 266)
    With Vance Thompson's note to A. P. N. Incomplete.
  - Page, Walter H. "Letter regarding copyrights of 'The Rosary.'", February 28, 1914 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 267)
    The Atlantic Monthly.
  - Paul, E.V.D. "The Story of 'The Rosary'," Screenland, Vol. 5, No. 2: p. 3, 10, April 8, 1922 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 268)
    Portland, Oregon. Paul is the brother-in-law of E. W. N.
  - Schumann-Heink, Ernestine. "How I Sing 'The Rosary:' With a Practical Talk to Young Singers about Concert Work", September 1902 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 269)
    Woman's Home Companion, P.13.
  - The Sewickley Valley paper, Vol. 6, February 23, 1901 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 270)
    Contains three articles about Nevin's death: "Ethelbert Nevin," "Nevin Music at the Second Presbyterian Church in Pittsburgh," "A Monument to Ethelbert Nevin."
  - Watt, Charles. "An Appreciation of Ethelbert Nevin", July 6, 1905 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 271)
    The Piano, p. 5. With a picture given to Charles Watt by Mrs. Ethelbert Nevin, New York. Charles Watt's Nevin Program in a separate folder.
  - Mid-Week Pictorial of the New York Times, January 9, 1935 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 272)
    Photocopy. Displays Nevin's piano.
  - The Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1950 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 273)
    Pitt [Magazine]. Not in Wang list or Word document.
  - Memorandum for Local Papers, November 24, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 274)
    University of Pittsburgh News. Not in Wang list or Word document.
  - Pitt News articles, 1934 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 275)
    Pitt News. Photocopy. With "Cathedral Memorial Room to Have a Portrait of Nevin." Not in Wang list or Word document. Two copies
    - Nevin's Brass Candlestick completes studio exhibit, March 27, 1934 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item a)
    - Cathedral memorial Room to have portrait of Nevin, Feb. 6, 1934 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Item b)
  - Saffron, Robert. Collegiate? Not Bert Nevin, '83, Says Biography (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 276)
    Pitt News. Not in Wang list or Word document.
  - Photo of Ethelbert Nevin, 1899 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 277)
    The Pittsburg(h) Bulletin. Not in Wang list or Word document
  - Producer Talks of New Films, April 12, 1951 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 278)
    Pittsburgh Post-Gazette
  - Lytle, Robert. "Twenty Manuscripts Donated to Pitt by Admirer of Noted Composer.", November 23, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 279)
    Pittsburgh Press. Not in Wang list or Word document.
  - Weiss, Anne. "Sister of Composer Prizes Manuscript", November 24, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 280)
    Pittsburgh Press. Photocopy.
  - Crawford Mitchell, Ruth. "Willa Cather at Queen Anne's Lodge", 1934 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 281)
    Pittsburgh Record. Photocopy. Not in Wang list or Word document. Missing
  - Network Will Carry Nevin Program Coast-to-Coast, November 23, 1933 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 282)
    Photocopy. With "In Mayfair" by Patricia Pitt.
  - Parlor Player, September 16, 1935 (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 283)
    Time Magazine. Pages 28 and 29.
  - Wolff, Cynthia Griffin. "New Cather Biographical Data "Valentine" Sentiments" (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 284)
    Not in Wang list or Word document. 1997-1998. Photocopy.
  - Winter Weddings (File-cabinet 18, Drawer 4, Folder 285)
    Unidentified Newspaper. Not in Wang list or Word document.
- Correspondence, 1880-1939; 1880-1901; VI.